從 YTS.MX 下載
Downloaded from
YTS.MX
YIFY 官方電影網站：YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
不是。
Ba.
不是！不是！
Ba! Ba!
不不不。
Ba, ba, ba.
- 再見。- 嗯，嗯？
- Bye.
- Ba, ba.
一堆器官，沒有來自大腦的自我火花…
A pile of organs without the spark of self
from a brain...
或從心臟泵出的血液。
or the pump of blood from a heart.
只是星期日午餐的屠夫托盤。
Just a butcher's tray for a Sunday lunch.
現在，誰願意重建器官？
Now, who would like
to reconstruct the organs?
如果有差別的話，誰能區分人類和動物呢？
And who can tell human from animal,
if there is a difference?
怎樣怎樣。
Come, come.
你小時候有玩過拼圖，不是嗎？
You did puzzles as children, did you not?
只有我這樣，還是在怪物說話時很難集中註意力？
Is it just me, or is it devilishly hard
to concentrate when the monster's talking?
他是一位非凡的外科醫生。
He is an extraordinary surgeon.
他的研究具有開創性。他的父親創立了這個地方。
His research is groundbreaking.
His father founded this place.
馬克斯·麥坎德爾斯，您是否誤認為自己參與了這場對話？
Have you mistaken yourself as included
in this conversation, Max McCandles?
您與我們的物理距離並非如此。
Your physical proximity to us
does not make it so.
滾蛋吧，老朋友。給自己買一套西裝吧
Fuck off, old pal. Get yourself a suit.
先生，你真的認為那是肝臟的歸宿嗎？
You really think
that's where the liver goes, sir?
請問先生，把它們放回去的目的是什麼？
Can I ask what is the purpose
of putting them back in, sir?
我的樂趣。
My amusement.
馬克斯·麥坎德爾斯先生！
Mr. Max McCandles!
課程結束時和我一起走。
Walk with me at the end of the lesson.
你的論文。
Your paper.
先生，您喜歡嗎？
You liked it, sir?
它顯示出傳統思維竭力接近平庸的跡象。
It showed signs of a conventional mind
straining hard to almost touch mediocrity.
- 謝謝。- 我需要一個人。一個項目的助理。
- Thank you.
- I need someone. An assistant on a project.
我喜歡。
I would love to.
- 你是個有宗教信仰的人嗎？- 我相信上帝。
- Are you a religious man?
- I believe in God.
- 我還是神？- 幽默，因為你通常被稱為...
- Me or the deity?
- Humorous, as you're often known as the...
這是我自己開的一個玩笑。
It is a joke of my own making.
我不需要為我解釋它。
I do not need it explicated for me.
真是魔鬼的傑作。
The very devil's work.
先生，您想過留鬍子嗎？
Have you thought of growing a beard, sir?
我看起來像一隻繫著領帶的大狗。
I look like a big dog in a cravat.
孩子們喜歡狗。
Kids like dogs.
這個工作。
This job.
是的。來。
Yes. Come.
上帝！上帝。
God! God.
上帝。
God.
- 你好。- 你好。
- Hello.
貝拉，這是麥坎德爾斯先生。
Bella, this is Mr. McCandles.
你好，貝拉。
Hello, Bella.
- 巴德。- 血。
- Bud.
- Blood.
- 巴德。- 血。
- Bud.
- Blood.
- 血。- 太棒了。
- Marvelous.
我很好。我很好。
I'm fine. I'm fine.
多麼漂亮的遲鈍啊。
What a very pretty retard.
她腦部受傷。
She suffered a brain injury.
我修好了。
I repaired it.
她的心理年齡和她的身體不太同步。
Her mental age and her body
are not quite synchronized.
語言來了。她正在以更快的速度進步。
Language is coming.
She is progressing at an accelerated pace.
她令人驚嘆。
She is stunning.
我需要仔細記錄她的進展。
I need to meticulously note her progression.
你會為我做這件事嗎？
You will do this for me?
這將是我的榮幸。
It would be my honor.
威！
Wee!
是的。這很令人興奮，貝拉。
Yes. It is exciting, Bella.
“嗚。” 我相信她正在做...
"Wee." I believe she's doing...
普里姆太太！
Mrs. Prim!
韋。
Wee.
你不喜歡醃魚嗎？
Do you not like kippers?
事實上，我很偏愛他們。
I am quite partial to them, actually.
我發現他們早上的樣子很好...
I find them to be nice in the morning...
貝拉也剪了？
Bella cut, too?
對貝拉來說只是死人。
Just dead ones for Bella.
剛剛死了。
Just dead.
壓扁！壓扁，壓扁。
Squish! Squish, squish.
時間！
Chog!
跑步！
Run!
什麼時候
Chog.
她每天收集 15 個單字。
She gathers 15 words a day.
她的協調性充其量也不穩定。
Her coordination is unstable at best.
到了晚上，就有進步了。
In the evenings, there's progress.
她的頭髮每兩天長長一吋。
Her hair grows one inch every two days.
- 我這裡有一張頭髮圖。- 出色的。
- I have a hair diagram here.
- Excellent.
你可以走了。明天見。
You may go. See you tomorrow.
先生，她從哪裡來？
Sir, where did she come from?
我相信你的工作就是收集數據。
I believe your job is collecting data.
當我添加一些愚蠢的問題時，我會讓你知道。
When I add inane questions to it,
I'll let you know.
「所以，當他們從樹林裡回來時...
"And so, when they returned from the wood...
「她與她的媽媽和爸爸團聚了。
"she was reunited with her Mummy and Daddy.
「那天晚上，晚餐時，他們吃了蛋糕，直到生病為止。
"That night, for dinner,
they ate cake until they were sick.
“他們很高興能重新聚在一起。”
"They were so happy to be back together."
你是我爸爸嗎，上帝？
You me Daddy, God?
- 我... - 波麗姆說你不是。
- I...
- Prim say you not be.
貝拉無處可去的女孩。
Bella nowhere girl.
那是哪裡？無處？
Where that be? Nowhere?
你是個孤兒。
You are an orphan.
你的父母死了。
Your parents died.
然後你就砍掉了父母，上帝？
Then you cut parents up, God?
不。
No.
他們是我的朋友。
They were my friends.
他們是勇敢的探險家...
They were brave explorers...
他們在南美洲的山崩中喪生。
and they were killed in a landslide
in South America.
他們突破了已知的界限......
They pushed the boundaries
of what was known...
他們付出了代價。
and they paid the price.
但這是唯一的生活方式，貝拉。
But that is the only way to live, Bella.
他們把你送到我這裡來照顧你。
They sent you to me to care for you.
死的？
Dead?
恐怕是這樣，親愛的。
I'm afraid so, my darling.
可憐的貝拉。
Poor Bella.
但愛神。
But love God.
在這裡睡。
Sleep here.
不。
No.
晚安，親愛的貝拉。
Good night, dear Bella.
這個，父母。
This, parents.
秘魯，是的。
Peru, yes.
為什麼你要寫下每一篇堅果？
Why you pen book every nut?
我必須記下你的營養攝取量。
I must note down your nutritional intake.
多少？
How many?
告訴貝拉其他地方。
Tell Bella other places.
那是葡萄牙的里斯本。
That's Lisbon, Portugal.
法國南部。阿爾卑斯山。
The south of France. The Alps.
澳大利亞。
Australia.
對人和動物來說，都是遙遠而危險的。
Far away and dangerous,
in both people and animal.
貝拉想要看看這個世界。
Bella want look at world.
只是...
Just...
貝拉。
Bella.
貝拉，我認為我們不被允許來這裡。
Bella, I don't think we're allowed up here.
讓我們...
Let's just...
貝拉。
Bella.
不。
No.
貝拉，這很危險。
Bella, this is dangerous.
貝拉。
Bella.
不，貝拉。
No, Bella.
上帝。
God.
必須去外面。
Outside must go.
外部？不，我們工作。
Outside? No, we work.
割傷手指？
Cut fingers?
蠟燭帶我走。蠟燭。
Candles take me.
Candles.
當然，我可以。如果...
Of course I can. If...
不。
No.
是的。出去！
Yes. Out!
她去過外面嗎？
Has she ever been outside?
不。
No.
我為貝拉創造了一個完美有趣且安全的世界。
I have created a perfectly entertaining
and safe world for Bella.
現在。
Now.
- 貝拉。- 現在！
- Bella.
- Now!
現在！
Now!
貝拉。
Bella.
你知道，外面有很多東西會殺死你，貝拉。
You know, so many things outside
can kill you, Bella.
殺死了？
Kill dead?
蛇、馬車、尖臉鳥、地震…
Snakes, carriages, sharp-faced birds,
earthquakes...
吸入有毒草籽。
inhalation of toxic grass seeds.
貝拉。
Bella.
貝拉。看。
Bella. Look.
- 殺了它。- 什麼？
- Kill it.
- What?
為什麼你的大拇指很滑稽，上帝？
Why you funny thumbs, God?
有一次，當我很小的時候...
Once when I was very small...
我父親把我的大拇指釘在一個小鐵盒裡…
my father pinned my thumbs
into a small iron case...
看看他是否可以延緩骨骼的生長週期。
to see whether he could retard
the growth cycle of bones.
現在，痛苦是如此之大…
Now, the pain was so great...
為了不讓自己哭泣...
to stop myself from weeping...
我會深深地凝視著我的其他手指......
I would stare deeply into my other fingers...
並簡單地透過觀察...
and simply by observation...
開始解析流行病學要素。
begin to parse out
the epidemiological elements.
當他回來時...
When he came back...
令他驚訝的是，我在微笑。
to his surprise, I was smiling.
天哪。
Good God.
他是一個思想非傳統的人。
He was a man of unconventional mind.
該走了。
Time to go.
暴風雨即將來臨。
A storm approaches.
為什麼要這麼嚇唬她？
Why must you scare her so?
她是個實驗品...
She's an experiment...
我必須控制條件...
and I must control the conditions...
否則我們的結果將不純淨。
or our results will not be pure.
停止！天哪，我們走吧！
Stop!
God, we go!
不，貝拉。
No, Bella.
貝拉想要在冰淇淋中散步。
Bella want walk in ice cream.
不。
No.
貝拉想要！
Bella wants!
我的臉。人們害怕上帝。
My face. People scared of God.
嘲笑上帝。
Laugh at God.
上帝可愛。
God lovely.
像狗臉一樣。
Like dog face.
相當。
Quite.
- 停止！我走。- 不！
- Stop! Me walk.
- No!
不是現在？沒有永不？
No now? No never?
就是不行。
Just no.
- 漂亮的！- 不！
- Bella!
- No!
- 不！不！不！- 漂亮的！
- No! No! No!
- Bella!
不！
No!
- 對不起。對不起。- 不！
- Sorry. Sorry.
- No!
不！不！
No! No!
對不起，親愛的。
I'm sorry, my darling.
聖母瑪利亞。
Mother of God.
你對她做了什麼？
What did you do to her?
為什麼要躲著她？
Why are you hiding her?
告訴我這一切意味著什麼，否則我就去報警。
Tell me what all this means,
or I'll go to the police.
我將。因為這是一個快樂的故事。
I shall. For it is a happy tale.
很難得到一具屍體，雖然已經死了，卻如此接近生命。
It is rare to get a body,
albeit dead, but so close to life.
嚴格性還沒出現。
Rigor had not set in.
身體幾乎還沒有冷卻。
The body had hardly cooled.
無脈搏。
No pulse.
但有一些電流，所以我可以讓她活下去。
But some electric currents,
so I could have kept her alive.
但你沒有。
But you didn't.
我對她所放棄的生活一無所知......
I knew nothing of the life
she had abandoned...
只是她太討厭它了，所以她選擇不…
except she hated it so much
that she had chosen not to be...
永遠。
and forever.
她會有什麼感覺…
What would she feel...
被從她精心挑選的空白永恆中拖出來…
on being dragged
from her carefully chosen blank eternity...
並被迫被安置在我們人手不足的一間...
and forced to be put
in one of our understaffed...
設備簡陋的瘋人院、管教所或監獄？
poorly-equipped madhouses,
reformatories or jails?
因為在這個基督教國家，自殺被視為精神錯亂或犯罪。
For in this Christian nation,
suicide is treated as lunacy or crime.
我是誰來決定她的命運？
Who was I to decide her fate?
但對我來說，也有一種認可。
But then there was also, on my part,
a recognition.
我所有的研究都到了這一刻。
All my research had come to this moment.
命運帶給我了一具屍體…
Fate had brought me a dead body...
和一個活生生的嬰兒。
and a live infant.
這是顯而易見的。
It was obvious.
它是？
It was?
把嬰兒的大腦取出...
Take the infant's brain out...
然後把它放進成年女人體內，讓她復活，然後觀察。
and put it in the full-grown woman,
reanimate her, and watch.
耶穌！
Jesus!
她知道？
She knows?
不。
No.
她是誰？
Who was she?
不知道。
No idea.
但你寧願這個世界沒有貝拉嗎？
But would you rather
the world did not have Bella?
普里姆太太？
Mrs. Prim?
貝拉在她想要的時候發現快樂。
Bella discover happy when she want.
你是一張臭臉，但我會修復你。
You are a sour face, but I fix you.
閉上眼睛。
Close eyes.
- 不！- 等等。這需要一點時間。
- No!
- Just wait. It takes a moment.
她搶走了我的生意。
She grabbed my hairy business.
她病了！
She's sick!
貝拉。
Bella.
貝拉發現了一些我必須分享的東西。
Bella have discover something I must share.
手錶。
Watch.
- 如果把黃瓜放進我體內會怎麼樣？- 不。
- What if put cucumber in me?
- No.
漂亮的！漂亮的！
Bella! Bella!
立即停止工作。
Cease working yourself immediately.
什麼？
What?
在上流社會，人們並沒有這麼做。
In polite society, that is not done.
只是不這樣做。
Just do not.
那是什麼？
What... is that?
我父親取出了我的催酸腺和幽門腺...
My father took out
my oxyntic and pyloric glands...
所以我必須自己做胃液。
so I must make my own gastric juices.
看在上帝的份上，他為什麼要這麼做？
Why in God's name would he do that?
去發現無人知曉的事。
To discover what no one knew.
事實證明我們需要它們。理想情況下。
Turns out we need them. Ideally.
貝拉…
Bella...
你還沒吃過。
you have not eaten.
不要。
Do not.
晚安。
Good night.
'夜晚。
'Night.
你知道，我其實是一個浪漫的人，麥克斯。
You know, I'm actually
something of a romantic, Max.
什麼？
What?
我相信我看到了你和貝拉之間的愛。
I believe I see love between you and Bella.
我……她是……
I... She is...
也許你應該娶她。
Perhaps you should marry her.
什麼？
What?
我想她愛你。
I think she loves you.
我看過人們彼此充滿愛意地看著對方
I've seen people look at each other
with love...
作為觀察者。
as an observer.
當然不是主題。我看到了。
Not the subject, of course. I see it.
你做？
You do?
我...
I...
我對她確實有感情。
I do have feelings for her.
那麼，你願意嗎？
So, you would?
帶貝拉出去。
Take Bella out.
貝拉…
Bella...
我...
I...
覺得好笑嗎？
Feel funny?
做貝拉吧
Do Bella.
我想知道...
I was wondering...
如果也許你正在撫養她成為你的情婦。
if perhaps you were raising her
to be your mistress.
我知道，這是一個不值得我的黑暗想法。
A dark thought unworthy of me, I know.
那麼，你不跟她上床了嗎？
So, you are not laying with her?
精子射精只能誘導我的體內平衡...
Spermatic ejaculation can only induce
homeostasis in me...
如果伴隨著對高級神經中樞的長時間刺激...
if accompanied by prolonged stimulation
of higher nerve centers...
它對無導管腺體的壓力改變了我血液的化學成分...
whose pressure on the ductless glands
changes the chemistry of my blood...
不是幾分鐘的痙攣…
not for a few spasmodic minutes...
但很多天了。
but for many days.
什麼？
What?
我是太監，不能幹她。
I am a eunuch and can't fuck her.
為了讓我的身體產生性反應...
To get a sexual response from my body...
所需的電量與倫敦北部的運轉電量相同。
would take the same amount of electricity
as runs North London.
另外，我的父愛之情…
Besides, my paternal feelings...
似乎超過了我的性想法。
seem to outweigh my sexual thoughts.
我為自己的陰暗想法道歉。
I apologize for my own dark thoughts.
一點也不黑。
Not dark at all.
男人的性行為，事實上所有的性行為，基本上都是不道德的。
Men's, indeed all sexuality,
is basically immoral.
不是全部，先生。
Not all, sir.
你想不想娶她？
Do you wish to marry her or not?
我想嫁給你。做我的妻子吧。
I wish to marry you. Be my wife.
讓我們觸摸彼此的生殖器。
Let us touch each other's genital pieces.
不，不。
No. No.
我不想利用你。
I do not wish to take advantage of you.
你很特別。
You are special.
當我們結婚的時候。
When we are wed.
一個條件。
One condition.
她一定也渴望它，我明白。
She must desire it also, I understand.
那麼有兩個條件。
Two conditions, then.
你說的那個...
That one you said...
你必須永遠和我住在這裡。
and you must live here with me, always.
我將起草一份法律協議。
I will have a legal agreement drawn up.
奇怪的合約。
Curious contract.
有幾個拼字錯誤。
There are several spelling errors.
我向你保證，這與它的法律約束力無關。
Immaterial to the legal bindingness of it,
I assure you.
必須是一位非常女性才能保證這樣的束縛。
Must be quite a woman
to warrant such binding.
請原諒，我需要使用這些設施。
If you'll excuse me,
I need to use the facilities.
你五歲了還不能控制水嗎？
Are you five years old
that you can't hold your water?
先生，膀胱無力。就像我之前的父親和他之前的父親一樣。
Weak bladder, sir.
Like my father before me and his before him.
您可能患有前列腺癌。了解更多。
You may have prostate cancer. Look into it.
會做。
Will do.
貝拉·巴克斯特女士，毫無疑問，按照您的合約。
Ms. Bella Baxter, as per your contract,
no doubt.
下午好，來訪的人。
Good afternoon, visiting man.
想要我的帽子嗎？
Want my hat?
它適合我嗎？
Would it suit me?
是的。
Yes.
這是愚蠢的好事。
It is foolish good.
我必須要見見這個女人...
I had to meet this woman...
誰會促成這樣一份囚禁她的婚約。
who would inspire such a contract of marriage
that imprisons her.
你是什​​麼意思？
What you mean?
你將住在這裡...
You shall live here...
與 Max McCandles 先生和 Baxter 先生一起出國旅行...
travel with Mr. Max McCandles
and Baxter abroad...
但不去城裡。
but not go forth in the city.
我懂了。
I see.
他們緊緊地愛著我。
They love me tight.
我明白為什麼。
I understand why.
我得掐你一下，看看你是不是真的。
I have to pinch you, to see if you are real.
你不會...
You will not...
你是誰？
Who is you?
鄧肯‧韋德伯恩先生。
Mr. Duncan Wedderburn.
打開。
Open.
你怎麼爬到這裡來了？
How you get up here?
我爬。
I climbed.
你監視我很久了？
You were watch me long?
不久。
Not long.
你沒有看到我透過自己的努力來獲得幸福，對嗎？
You did not see me working on myself
to get happiness, did you?
我知道這不是禮貌。
It is not polites, I know.
不關心上流社會。
Do not care for polite society.
真他媽無聊。
It's fucking boring.
摧毀一個人的靈魂。
Destroys one's soul.
上帝不相信靈魂。
God not believe in soul.
我認為上帝是靈魂觀念的真正創造者。
I think God's the actual author
of the soul idea.
戈德溫·巴克斯特？
Godwin Baxter?
那隻被燒死的狗。
That burnt dog.
那是什麼故事？
What is that story?
你是一名囚犯，我的目標是釋放你。
You are a prisoner and I aim to free you.
你內在的某些東西，一些飢餓的存在...
Something in you, some hungry being...
渴望體驗、自由、觸摸。
hungry for experience, freedom, touch.
看到未知並認識它。
To see the unknown and know it.
那麼，你問我為什麼在這裡？
So, why am I here, you ask?
我周五要去里斯本。我希望你能來。
I'm going to Lisbon on Friday.
I'd like you to come.
葡萄牙里斯本？
Lisbon of Portugal?
這就是我所說的里斯本。
That is the Lisbon I speak of.
上帝絕對不允許。
God never allow it.
這就是為什麼我不問他。
That's why I'm not asking him.
我在問你。
I'm asking you.
我想貝拉和你在一起並不安全。
Bella not safe with you, I think.
你絕對……不是。
You are absolutely... not.
親愛的上帝，可以給我一段寶貴的時間嗎？
May I have a moment of value time, dear God?
當然，貝拉。
Of course, Bella.
我想告訴你一個大消息。
I wanted to tell you big news.
貝拉興奮得頭暈。
Bella is dizzy with excite.
它是什麼？
What is it?
今晚，半夜…
Tonight, at midnight...
我和鄧肯‧韋德伯恩偷偷私奔了。
I secretly run away
with one Duncan Wedderburn.
什麼？
What?
你會想阻止我。
You will wish to stop me.
我會阻止你的。
I shall stop you.
你把貝拉抱得太緊了。
You hold Bella too tight.
我必須出發進入水域。
I must set forth into waters.
我們可以旅行。
We can travel.
你、我和麥克斯，我會提醒你…
You, me, and Max whom,
I will remind you...
你已經訂婚了。
you are betrothed to.
我要嫁給麥斯...
I will marry Max...
因為他似乎適合這樣做...
as he seems right for that...
但首先，我要在鄧肯·韋德伯恩 (Duncan Wedderburn) 上冒險…
but first, I shall adventure
on Duncan Wedderburn...
我想，誰不在乎我所受的傷害…
who, I think, cares little of damage to me...
但也會很有趣。
but will be interesting as well.
我不能讓你走。
I can't let you go.
吻我並帶我出去。
Kiss me and set me forth.
如果你不...
If you do not...
貝拉的內心將會因仇恨而腐爛。
Bella's insides shall turn rotten with hate.
- 恨？- 恨。
- Hate?
- Hate.
打開那些袋子，波麗姆。
Unpack those bags, Prim.
戈德溫已經告訴我你的計畫了。
Godwin has told me your plan.
我不怪你，貝拉。
I do not blame you, Bella.
那個人是個無賴和浪子。
That man is a cad and a rake.
他用陰險的方式激怒天真的女人。
He has insidious ways
of getting under a naive woman's skin.
主要是他的眼睛看著我。
It is mostly his eyes on mine.
當他的手放在貝拉的雙腿之間時...
And his hands when between Bella's legs...
並低聲說出我聽不見的話語…
and whisper words I can't hear...
但我的身體卻發熱。
but heat in my body.
天哪，貝拉。
Jesus, Bella.
我們訂婚了。
We are engaged.
我愛你。
I love you.
等我回來了，我們就結婚了…
And when I return, we marriage...
並像樹枝上的兩隻鴿子一樣快樂。
and be happy as two doves on a branch.
- 你認為我需要旅行帽嗎？- 不！
- You think I need travel hat?
- No!
這是不行的。
This will not do.
這不行！
It cannot!
我會親自去看看這個人。
I'll see to this man myself.
我要把他英俊的臉打成血骨粥！
I will beat his handsome face
into a porridge of blood and bones!
麥克斯，你臉紅了…
Max, you are flushed...
我也看到了不同的麥克斯。
and I am too at sight of different Max.
我道歉...
I apologize...
但我不會讓一個我認識的人心裡只有惡意…
but I will not let a man that I know
has nothing but ill intent in his mind...
他心裡對你沒有什麼欺騙你的。
and nothing for you in his heart trick you.
我要打碎他的頭。
I will smash his fucking head in.
貝拉？它...
Bella? It...
貝拉。
Bella.
再見，稍後的鴿子。
Goodbye, later dove.
偉大的冒險之後我會見到你。
I will see you after grand adventure.
上帝？
God?
她走了。
She's gone.
我早餐吃波特酒。
I am having port for breakfast.
真是奇怪的美味。
It is strangely delicious.
為什麼不阻止她？
Why did you not stop her?
她是一個有自由意志的人。
She is a being of free will.
她現在就在外面。獨自的。
She's now out there. Alone.
她會沒事的。
She will be fine.
我是一個傻瓜。我應該阻止她的。
I'm a fool. I should have stopped her.
我們是科學人。
We are men of science.
這種情緒化是不恰當的。
This emotionality is unseemly.
我只希望她一切都好。
I just hope she's all right.
你是我見過的最美麗的女人。
You are the most beautiful woman
I've ever seen.
我不會說謊，我和很多人在一起過。
I will not lie, I have been with many.
普里姆太太說你是狼，身上有一百個女人的氣味。
Mrs. Prim said you were wolf
with scent of hundred women on you.
她低估了它。
She undersells it.
好的。生蠔。
Okay. Oysters.
你以前吃過嗎？
Have you had them before?
我沒有。
I have not.
去殼、卡盤和泡沫。
Shuck, chuck and bubble.
歡鬧。
Rollicking.
等待。貝拉。
Wait. Bella.
所以，尼姑和僧侶會用蛋白為衣服上漿…
So, nuns and monks would
starch their clothes with egg whites...
然後，用蛋黃製作這些餡餅。
and, with the yolks, make these tarts.
現在，怎麼吃它們呢？
Now, how to eat them?
我會透過嘴巴猜測。
I will guess through the mouth.
他們不可以一片一片地吃下去…
They must not be eaten
dainty flake by dainty flake...
但卻充滿熱情地吸入，就像生命本身一樣。
but inhaled with gusto, like life itself.
極好的。
Incredible.
這些是誰做的？我們需要更多。
Who made these?
We need more.
不再。一個就夠了 再多就太多了。
No more. One's enough.
Any more is too much.
午睡時間到了。
It's siesta time.
什麼是午睡？
What is siesta?
為什麼人們不這樣做...
Why do people not just do this...
每時每刻？
all the time?
好吧，冒著不謙虛的風險...
Well, at the risk of being immodest...
你剛剛被最好的人操過三次。
you've just been thrice fucked
by the very best.
很可能沒有其他人能讓你達到我所擁有的狂喜。
It's probable no other man
would ever bring you to the raptures I have.
我為你感到傷心。
I feel bad for you.
好吧，那我就只能和你一起瘋狂地跳躍了。
Well, then it will just be you
I do furious jumping with.
狂暴跳躍？
Furious jumping?
我喜歡那個。
I love that.
我休息了。
I'm rested.
讓我們再出發吧。
Let us go again.
再一次？
Again?
很遺憾...
Unfortunately...
即使我也有我的極限。
even I have my limits.
男人不能總是回來索取更多。
Men cannot keep coming back for more.
這是生理問題嗎？
It is a physiological problem?
男人的弱點？
A weakness in men?
出色地...
Well...
也許是這樣。
Perhaps so.
如果還不算太晚的話，我會建議您...
You'd be advised,
if it's not too late...
不要愛上我。
not to fall in love with me.
我能提供的東西很少...
I have very little to offer...
以恆常之道。
in the way of constancy.
只是冒險。
Just adventure.
我懂了。
I see.
讓我們睡吧。
Let us sleep.
出租車，女士？
Taxi, madam?
晚安...
Good evening...
鄧肯·韋德伯恩。
Duncan Wedderburn.
貝拉，你在哪裡？你消失了。
Bella, where were you? You disappeared.
我沒有。
I did not.
沒有人可以憑空消失。
Nobody can just disappear.
什麼？
What?
他們可以嗎？消失？
Can they? Disappear?
不，當然不是。你他媽在說什麼…
No, of course not.
What the fuck are you talking...
當時你在哪裡？
Where were you?
我想要一個餡餅，然後一次冒險降臨到我身上。
I wanted a tart
and then an adventure befell me.
我不知道如何返回，然後我聽到了。
I did not know how to return
and then I heard it.
電車。
The tram.
我將走到噪音處，然後我找到了它。
I will walk to the noise, and I found it.
讓貝拉驚訝不已。
Amazement to Bella.
我體內流著探險家的血液。
Explorer bloods in me.
貝拉，不帶我出去很危險。
Bella, it's dangerous to go out without me.
我冒險過，但除了糖和暴力之外什麼也沒發現。
I have adventured it
and found nothing but sugar and violence.
這是最迷人的。
It is most charming.
我沒事。
I am fine.
現在，我必須躺下，你也必須躺在我身上，進行更猛烈的跳躍。
Now, I must lie down and you must lie down
on top of me and do more furious jumping.
貓咪。
Kitty.
你看過王爾德在倫敦的新劇嗎？
Did you see the new show in London by Wilde?
非常機智。
Marvelously witty.
我愛它。
I loved it.
“一個手提包。”
"A handbag."
貝拉。
Bella.
什麼？
What?
如果它令人反感，為什麼我要把它留在嘴裡？
Why I keep it in my mouth if it is revolting?
我之前曾對傑拉德說過這句話。
I have said that before to Gerald.
如果你明白我的意思。
If you catch my drift.
你是邪惡的。
You are wicked.
哦。因為你指的是他的陰莖。
Oh. Because you mean his penis.
鄧肯的有時會很鹹。
Duncan's can sometimes be salty.
天啊，貝拉。
Good God, Bella.
我必須去打那個孩子。
I must go punch that baby.
貝拉。
Bella.
你的行為是不合情理的。
Your behavior is unconscionable.
你會表現得好嗎？
Will you behave?
食物卡住了我的喉嚨…
The food was cacking my throat...
寶寶煩人...
the baby annoying...
女人的言語令人厭煩。
and the woman boring with words.
你將重新加入餐桌...
You will rejoin the table...
並將自己限制在以下三個短語中...
and will confine yourself
to the following three phrases...
「太棒了！」、「高興極了」…
"How marvelous!", "Delighted"...
以及“他們是怎麼把糕點做得這麼脆的？” 是的？
and "How did they make the pastry so crisp?"
Yes?
你傷害了貝拉。
You are hurting Bella.
對不起。
Sorry.
理性無法滲透。
Reason does not penetrate.
讓我們去。
Let us go.
貝拉，你喜歡里斯本嗎？
Are you enjoying Lisbon, Bella?
高興極了。
Delighted.
凱蒂，你親愛的爸爸怎麼樣？
Kitty, how is your dear father?
他身體很不好。
He's very unwell.
我擔心他今年都看不到了。
I fear he will not see the year out.
多麼奇妙。
How marvelous.
他們是怎麼把糕點做得這麼脆的呢？
How did they get the pastry so crisp?
天哪。
Good God.
它是什麼？
What is it?
從她。
From her.
「我很好。里斯本。
"Me good. Lisbon.
“糖塔舔我一整天。”
"Sugar tart lick me all day."
無論如何，至少我希望這只是一句話。
At least I hope
that's all one sentence, anyway.
- 你認為他們是... - 他媽的？
- Do you think they're...
- Fucking?
是的。
Yes.
也...
Also...
砍伐一輛電車。
fellating a tram.
鄧肯‧韋德伯恩，妳的頭也痛嗎？
Does your head ache too, Duncan Wedderburn?
而且我也餓了，想吃晚餐了。
And I also am starving for dinner.
你他媽的在哪裡？
Where the fuck were you?
維多利亞·布萊辛頓？
Victoria Blessington?
我已經好幾年沒見到你了。
I haven't seen you for years.
而你還沒有...
And you still have not...
因為我是貝拉·巴克斯特…
as I am Bella Baxter...
奇怪的羽毛女士。
strange feathered lady.
我道歉。我可以發誓你就是她。
I apologize. I could've sworn you were she.
正確的。
Right.
我們可以？
Shall we?
牛排、魚…
The steak, the fish...
罐子裡的小焦糖東西...
little caramel things in pots...
那邊的老斑點人都有。
that old spotted people over there have.
我不想在罐子裡放焦糖。
I don't want caramel in pots.
當然不是。這就是貝拉的全部了。
Of course not. That was all for Bella.
隨心所欲地訂購。
Order at your whim.
你對貝拉的郊遊和冒險很生氣。
You are cross
at Bella's outings and adventures.
然而我們必須突發奇想地發現...
And yet we must discover by whim...
正如鄧肯·韋德伯恩 (Duncan Wedderburn) 對貝拉·巴克斯特 (Bella Baxter) 所說…
as spoken by Duncan Wedderburn
to Bella Baxter...
里斯本戀情的第一天。
day one of Lisbon love affair.
觸碰。
Touché.
請理解我從未在上帝的家之外生活過。
Understand me never lived
outside God's house.
什麼？
What?
所以，貝拉有太多的發現...
So, Bella so much to discover...
還有你悲傷的臉...
and your sad face...
讓我發現對你有憤怒的感覺。
makes me discover angry feelings for you.
正確的。
Right.
我變成了我最討厭的人…
I have become the very thing I hate...
貪得無厭的情人魅魔。
a grasping succubus of a lover.
我已經把很多人從我身上撬開，現在我就是了。
I've pried many of them off me
and now I'm it.
他媽的！
Fuck!
你和我一樣，都是當下自由的生物。
You, like me, are a creature of freedom
in the moments.
你一直這樣做是為了什麼？
What do you keep doing that for?
那邊有個男人不斷地對我眨眼。
A man over there repeated blinks at me.
我眨了眨眼。
I blink back.
我認為是出於禮貌。
For polites, I think.
我們要去城裡跳舞。請加入我們。
We are going to dance in town.
Please join us.
我從來沒有在城裡跳舞過。
I have never danced in town.
- 鄧肯！- 不能！
- Duncan!
- Can't!
你真是太生氣了。
You're quite mad.
別說話了，你的聲音會讓貝拉生氣！
Stop talking
as your sounds make Bella angry!
我不會停止說話。
I will not stop talking.
如果我有話要說，我會...
If I have something to say I'll...
哎喲。
Ouch.
好的。
All right.
這是什麼？
What's this?
一個人教我下棋...
A man was teaching me chess...
他說他認為我的皮膚可能是他接觸過的最柔軟的。
and he said he thought I would probably have
the softest skin he had ever touched.
我說，如果我這樣做的話，那就是測試大腿內側…
And I said, if I did it would be
the inner thighs to test...
因為那是表皮最細的地方。
as that is where the epidermis
is at its most fine.
所以我們測試了...
So we tested...
這是有史以​​來最柔軟的。
and it was the softest ever.
我想知道他們在溫柔方面是否不平等。
I wondered if perhaps
they're not equal in softitude.
事實上他們不是。
Indeed they were not.
所以我一定要記下來，記得哪個是哪個。
So I made sure to note it,
remembering which was which.
你要表演什麼舌頭劇？
What of the tongue play
you were about to perform?
這不是發生了嗎？
Is that not happening?
你...
You...
你很煩惱。
You are troubled.
他對你撒謊了嗎？
Did he lie with you?
不，我們是靠牆了。
No, we were against a wall.
你有沒有生氣地跳他？
Did you furious jump him?
不，他只是快速舔了我的陰蒂。
No, he just fast-licked my clitoris.
我有需要釋放的熱量，所以按照我的要求釋放了。
I had the heat that needed release,
so at my request it was.
你也可以用舌頭來玩我…
You, too, may tongue play me...
所以我無法理解這種複雜的感覺。
so I'm not understanding
this complicated feeling.
你現在在哭嗎？
Are you now crying?
你真是個令人困惑的人，鄧肯·韋德伯恩。
What a confusing person you are,
Duncan Wedderburn.
一個肝臟。
A liver.
一個小切口...
A small incision...
這就是所需要的一切。
is all that is needed.
整個早上我都是氯仿山羊。
I was chloroforming goats all morning.
我可能攝取太多了。
I may have ingested too much.
我冒昧地告訴你，貝拉的缺席讓你感到不安。
I am going to venture to suggest
you are upset by Bella's absence.
波特酒的升數...
The liters of port...
我晚上聽到的抽泣聲。
the sobbing I hear at night.
天哪，夥計！你像個白痴一樣胡言亂語。
Good God, man! You prattle like an imbecile.
她走了！
She is gone!
我是一個科學人。
I am a man of science.
我只需要參與並繼續這個專案。
I just need to engage in,
and continue, the project.
就這些。我必須繼續下一件事。
That is all.
I must go on to the next thing.
我們的感情必須放在一邊。
Our feelings must be put aside.
你認為我父親會給我烙印嗎？
Do you think my father
could have branded me...
像他那樣用熱熨斗燙生殖器…
with hot irons on the genitals
the way he did...
如果他不能把科學和進步放在第一位呢？
if he could not put
science and progress first?
給你打上烙印了嗎？
Branded you?
讓我們找出一具屍體。
Let us find a body.
一個什麼？
A what?
你好。早安.
Hello. Good morning.
早安，親愛的。
Good morning, darling.
我不太支持你的冒險精神。
I haven't been very supportive
of your adventurous spirit.
所以我要給你一個驚喜。
So I have a surprise for you.
進來。
Get in.
- 我們換了飯店？- 看看窗外，貝拉。
- We changed hotels?
- Look out the window, Bella.
- 我們在船上？- 的確。
- We're on boat?
- Indeed.
- 你的目標是把貝拉困在海上。- 我的目標是給你一個新的冒險。
- You aim to trap Bella at sea.
- I aim to give you a new adventure.
我想這是真的，你會更容易找到。
I suppose it's true you'll be easier to find.
來吧，脫掉我的衣服。
Come, disrobe me.
騎我吧
Ride me.
然後我們將在前甲板上喝雞尾酒。
And we'll then have cocktails on foredeck.
貝拉。
Bella.
貝拉！
Bella!
藍色的。藍色的。藍色的。
Blue. Blue. Blue.
罵我？
Shit on me?
笨蛋！
Fucker!
女士。
Madam.
我們什麼時候停下來？
When do we stop?
雅典。三天。
Athens. Three days.
那個女人火了，你看。
That woman's on fire, look.
我知道你對我很生氣。
I know you're upset with me.
原諒我綁架了你，但那是為了愛情。
Forgive my kidnapping of you,
but it was for love.
浪漫的笑話。別這麼小氣。
A romantic jape.
Don't be such a cunt about it.
- 我想喝一杯。- 當然，親愛的。
- I want a drink.
- Of course, my darling.
這艘船很有趣，有一個值得探索的世界。
The ship is fun, a whole world to explore.
你愛我嗎？我愛你。
Do you love me? I love you.
明確描述我應該在自己身上尋找的元素。
Describe the elements I should be looking for
within myself to be sure.
你只是感覺到或感覺不到。
You just feel it or not.
因此，正如上帝所說，這不是證據基礎。
So it is no evidence base, as God would say.
- 那麼如何憑經驗判斷呢？- 你他媽的在說什麼？
- So how judge it empirically?
- What the fuck are you talking about?
你是誰？
Who are you?
你不知道香蕉是什麼，你從來沒有聽過西洋棋...
You don't know what bananas are,
you've never heard of chess...
但你知道「經驗」是什麼意思。
and yet you know what "empirically" means.
貝拉想要喝一杯。我現在說了兩次。
Bella wants a drink. I said twice now.
我從未有過這樣的感覺。
I've never felt anything like this.
這對你來說是真的嗎？
Is this true for you?
我想，從經驗上來說確實如此。
I suppose, empirically it is.
我的墨水沒了。
I'm out of ink.
那你就擁有墨水了，我的愛人。
Then ink you shall have, my love.
你好，有趣的老太太。
Hello, interesting older lady.
我必須摸摸你的頭髮。
I must touch your hair.
我還注意到你的頭髮。
I also noticed your hair.
就像半透明發光雞蛋上的絲綢一樣。
Just like silk on a translucent, glowing egg.
這是一些奇特的詞，不知何故讓我興奮。
That is fancy words that excite me somehow.
我看到你和帥哥在一起了
I saw you're with handsome over there.
潔白的牙齒和堅硬的雞雞。
White teeth and a hard cock.
鄧肯·韋德伯恩。
Duncan Wedderburn.
他的牙齒也很硬。他的陰莖也是白色的。
His teeth are also hard.
His penis is also white.
- 好的，我希望。- 他是我唯一的。
- Good lay, I hope.
- He is my only.
但我發現他在我的整個身體中引起了特殊的感覺...
But I find him to elicit exceptional
sensations throughout my whole body...
這讓我高興地大喊。
that leave me yelping happily.
我也想把他的身體、形體、屍體，丟進海裡。
I also wish to dash his body, form, cadaver,
into the sea.
這個男人跳到你身上了嗎？
Is this man jumping on your body?
他不是。
No, he is not.
我已經20年沒有上床睡覺了。
I haven't been bedded in 20 years.
什麼？
What?
太糟糕了。
That is terrible.
這對我來說並不重要。
It doesn't concern me greatly.
隨著歲月的流逝...
As years have passed...
我最關心的是我耳朵之間的東西。
what's in between my ears
is my big concern.
我的兩腿之間有什麼...
What's in between my legs...
更不如此。
much less so.
絕望的合理化，瑪莎。
A desperate rationalization, Martha.
哦，這是哈利·阿斯特利。
Oh, this is Harry Astley.
別太把他的話放在心上。
Don't take what he says too much to heart.
他是個憤世嫉俗的人。
He's a cynic.
女士。
Madam.
我是貝拉·巴克斯特。
I am Bella Baxter.
我不知道這個「憤世嫉俗」是什麼。
I do not know what this "cynic" is.
貝拉。
Bella.
墨水。
Ink.
鄧肯‧韋德伯恩（Duncan Wedderburn），我結交了朋友、同事、同志。
Duncan Wedderburn,
I have made friends, colleagues, comrades.
哈里·阿斯特利。
Harry Astley.
這是瑪莎。
This is Martha.
她是我的新朋友，已經20年沒有被幹過了。
She is my new friend who has not been fucked
in 20 years.
這不是驚訝嗎？
Is that not astonishment?
我希望你把手放在兩腿之間，讓自己保持快樂。
I hope you use your hand between your legs
to keep yourself happy.
天哪，貝拉，你不能這樣說話。
Good God, Bella,
you cannot speak like this.
社會的有禮貌的人。我忘了。
Polites of society. I forgot.
文明社會...
Polite society...
會毀了你。
will destroy you.
- 它會？- 是的，這有一定道理。
- It will?
- Yeah, there's some truth to that.
我們都同意這一點。
We all agreed on that.
至於你向我提出的詢問。
As to your enquiry on my hand.
偶爾，是的。
Occasionally, yes.
這是一個非常令人放心的消息。
That is much reassuring news.
- 我們大家一起吃飯。- 實際上...
- We shall all dine together.
- Well, actually...
我們都在船上，無法逃脫…
We are all on a ship and cannot escape...
這裡有一個值得享受、穿越、環遊的世界。
and there is a world to enjoy,
traverse, circumnavigate.
或者她就不能有朋友嗎，韋德伯恩先生？
Or can she not have friends, Mr. Wedderburn?
高興極了。
Delighted.
嫁給我吧。
Marry me.
什麼？
What?
我本來想把你丟到一邊的。
I meant to throw you aside.
幾個月後，我會送你打包行李，但我不能。
A few months and send you packing,
but I cannot.
說你要嫁給我。從來沒有人擄獲我的心。你有。
Say you'll marry me.
No one's ever captured my heart. You have.
這很棘手...
It is tricky...
因為我與馬克斯·麥坎德爾斯先生訂婚了。
as I am engaged to Mr. Max McCandles.
什麼？
What?
我的手被另一隻手握住了。
My hand has taken by another.
這是我聽過的一句話，但不明白。
It is a saying I heard,
but did not understand.
你不只是握住手，而是握住全部，不是嗎？
You do not take just the hand,
but all, do you not?
你帶著我逃離了他。
You ran away with me from him.
對事件的重述，其意義對我來說難以捉摸。
A recounting of events,
the point of which is elusive to me.
你選擇了我而不是他。
You chose me over him.
目前。
For now.
為了娛樂。
For fun.
我他媽的會把你丟到海裡去！
I'll fucking throw you overboard!
所以你想娶我還是殺我？
So you wish to marry me or kill me?
- 這是提案嗎？- 不。
- Is that the proposal?
- No.
去賭場。
Going to the casino.
沒關係。
That's fine.
她也跟著來了。
She is coming along.
讓我們再試一次。
Let's try again.
粗大動作技能會慢慢發展...
Gross motor skills will develop slowly...
但你會進步很快。
but you will progress fast.
費莉西蒂。
Felicity.
沒那麼快。
Not that fast.
我正在讀愛默生。
I am reading Emerson.
他談到了人類的進步。
He speaks about the improvement of men.
我不知道他為什麼不給女性建議。
I do not know why
he does not give advice to women.
也許他什麼都不知道。
Perhaps he does not know any.
嘗試閱讀歌德。
Try and read Goethe.
哲學是浪費時間，貝拉。
Philosophy is a waste of time, Bella.
真的嗎？說多一點。
Really? Say more.
不，不，哈利，你這個壞蛋。
No, no, Harry, you wretch.
它是不可或缺的。
It is integral.
人和社會都可以得到改善。
People and society can be improved.
改進、進步、進步、成長是所有人的目標。
It is the goal of all to improve,
advance, progress, grow.
我知道我身上有這一點，我確信我代表了一切。
I know this in me,
and I am sure I am indicative of all.
相信我，貝拉，你在各方面都絕對是獨一無二的。
Trust me, you are definitely unique, Bella,
in all ways.
但這種透過哲學的改進......
But this improvement through philosophy...
人們試圖逃避我們都是殘忍的野獸這一事實。
is people trying to run away from the fact
that we are all cruel beasts.
那樣出生，那樣死去。
Born that way, die that way.
這是一種陰暗的看法，哈利。
It is a dark view of things, Harry.
貝拉…
Bella...
讓我們呼吸空氣...
let us take the air...
在我們的小屋裡。
in our cabin.
但這兩人卻在打架…
But these two are fighting...
各種想法在貝拉的腦海和心中盤旋…
and ideas are banging around
in Bella's head and heart...
就像暴風雨中的燈光。
like lights in a storm.
你現在總是在讀書，貝拉。
You're always reading now, Bella.
你正在失去一些可愛的說話方式。
You're losing some of your adorable way
of speaking.
我是一場變幻的盛宴…
I am a changingable feast...
我們所有人也是如此。
as are all of we.
顯然，根據愛默生的說法，哈利不同意。
Apparently according to Emerson,
disagreed with by Harry.
來來。來吧。
Come, come. Just come.
你在我的陽光下。
You are in my sun.
什麼？
What?
來。
Come.
忙著喝酒。
Busy drinking heavily.
忙著損失慘重。
Busy losing heavily.
我必須去見瑪莎。
I must go meet Martha.
瑪莎。
Martha.
她就是問題所在。
She is the problem.
我會把那袋散發著香味的肉丟到海裡。
I'll throw that
perfumed bag of flesh overboard.
我賭你。
I dare you.
瑪莎！
Martha!
她在哪？
Where is she?
你在哪兒，他媽的。
Where are you, fuck.
她在哪？
Where is she?
- 你要去哪裡？- 她要翻到一邊了。
- Where are you going?
- She's going over the side.
哦，太棒了！
Oh, marvelous!
我從沒想過自己會被謀殺。
I never imagined being murdered.
多麼戲劇化。
How dramatic.
嗯，看來她死的很開心。很抱歉妨礙你了。
Well, she seems happy to die.
I'm sorry for getting in your way.
令人興奮。
Exciting.
我會在酒吧。
I'll be in the bar.
你讓我思考、思考…
You have made me think, cogitate...
反覆思考錯誤的想法...
perambulate on ideas that are wrong...
錯誤且無意義的煩人...
erroneous and nonsensically annoying...
這導致我無法入睡。
that lead me not to sleep.
所以...
So...
你說一切都是殘酷的。
You say all are cruel.
我不同意，否認...
And I disagree, disavow...
並說不。
and say no not.
但當和鄧肯在一起時...
But when with Duncan...
殘酷的事在我心裡冒泡。
the cruel just bubbles up in me.
這表明了良好的判斷力。
That shows good judgment.
他是個漂亮的白痴。
He is a pretty moron.
不。
No.
我不想變得殘忍。
I do not wish to be cruel.
我必須提升自己的這一方面。
I must improve this aspect of myself.
你不了解這個世界。
You don't know the world.
你害怕它。
And you fear it.
我不害怕它。
I do not fear it.
你想看看世界到底是什麼樣子嗎？
Do you want to see what the world
is really like?
我會給你看。
I'll show you.
是的。
Yes.
當然。
Of course.
你聽到了嗎？
Do you hear that?
它是什麼？
What is it?
很多死去的嬰兒。
Lot of dead babies.
一定很熱。
Must be hot.
我們必須去幫助他們。
We must go help them.
我們將如何做到這一點？
How will we do that?
我們去那裡...
We go down there...
他們會理所當然地繩索我們、搶劫我們、強暴我們。
they'll quite rightfully rope us,
rob us, and rape us.
如果他們在這裡而我們在那裡......
And if they were here
and we were there...
我們也會對他們做同樣的事情。
we'd do the same to them.
貝拉。
Bella.
我們要離開了，女士。
We are casting off, ma'am.
但我必須回去。
But I have to go back.
我必須把這筆錢送給飯店附近的窮人...
I must give this money
to the poor near the hotel...
在他們所謂的貧民窟裡。
in what they call a slum.
我們留在岸上，女士。
We're staying ashore, ma'am.
我們可以為您解決這個問題。
We could take care of that for you.
你可以？
You can?
當然。
Of course.
你真慷慨。
It is generous of you.
他們需要錢。
They need money.
每個人都這樣做。
Everyone does.
謝謝。
Thank you.
你！給我找隊長吧 現在我們要找到這個該死的小偷。
You! Get me the captain.
Now we'll find this fucking thief.
貝拉！
Bella!
我們被搶劫了！
We've been robbed!
我贏了。
I won.
我贏得了一切...
I won everything...
前所未有。
like never before.
現在它消失了。
And now it's gone.
你沒有被搶劫。
You've not been robbed.
- 我拿了。- 為了什麼？
- I took it.
- For what?
我拿了。
I took it.
我好累。
I'm so tired.
或者也許只是我的精神。
Or maybe just my spirit is.
我的靈魂已經被扭曲、扭曲了…
My soul has been buckled, crumpled...
扁平化，鄧肯‧韋德伯恩…
flattened, Duncan Wedderburn...
就我所見過的景點而言。
by the sights I have seen.
- 那麼，那就不需要船長了，長官？- 在我打碎你所有的牙齒之前滾開。
- So, no need for the captain then, sir?
- Fuck off before I break all your teeth.
確實如此，先生。
Indeed, sir.
它在哪裡？
Where is it?
為了安全你把它藏起來了。
You hid it for safety.
我喝醉了，愚蠢地把它丟得到處都是。終於解脫了。
I was drunk and foolishly left it everywhere.
What a relief.
我沒有隱藏它。
I did not hide it.
我把它給了那裡的那些窮人。
I gave it to those poor people out there.
金錢本身就是一種疾病…
Money is its own form of sickness...
以及它的所有稀缺性。
and all the scarcity of it.
而我是誰...
And who am I...
躺在羽毛床上…
lying in a feather bed...
當死去的嬰兒...
while dead babies...
躺在溝裡？
lie in a ditch?
鄧肯.
Duncan.
你什麼？
You what?
我期待著一個安慰的擁抱。
I am expecting a hug of solace.
你...
You...
我需要向世界提供一些東西。
I need to offer something
to the world.
而我卻一無所有。
And yet I have nothing.
除了一些錢。
Except some money.
對貝拉·巴克斯特來說，這是糟糕的一天。
It is a bad day for Bella Baxter.
我他媽的錢在哪裡？
Where is my fucking money?
我剛剛告訴過你了。
I just told you.
我把它送給了窮人。
I gave it away to the poor.
我以為我叫你滾開！
I thought I told you to fuck off!
管家通知我...
The steward informs me...
先生，您可能沒有足夠的資金來償還您的帳戶。
that you may not have sufficient funds
to make good your account, sir.
- 嗯，我... - 這可能是真的。
- Well, I...
- That is probably true.
我把一切都給了一些好人...
I gave it all to some nice men...
傳遞...
to pass on...
給貧民窟的窮人。
to the slum poor.
你將在下一個港口被送上岸...
You'll be put ashore at the next port...
在此之前僅限於船員的口糧，長官。
and confined to crew's rations
until then, sir.
- 晚安. - 你怎麼敢？
- Good evening.
- How dare you?
「死了，瞎眼的嬰兒......
"Dead, blind babies...
」哈利咬了一口。
"bit Harry.
「我的嘴巴...
"My mouth...
“渾身是血。”
"was full of blood."
可憐的貝拉。
Poor Bella.
她是一片廢墟。
She is a ruin.
- 你的手怎麼樣？- 沒關係。
- How's your hand?
- It's fine.
對不起。
I'm sorry.
你試著幫助我理解。
You were trying to help me understand.
不，我其實是想傷害你。
No. I actually wanted to hurt you.
無法忍受看到某人如此愚蠢而美麗的幸福。
Couldn't bear to see such dumb,
beautiful happiness in someone.
這對我來說太殘酷了。
It was cruel of me.
我不後悔。
I am not sorry.
如果我了解這個世界，我就能改善它。
If I know the world, I can improve it.
你不能。
You can't.
這才是真正的重點。
That is the real point.
不要接受宗教的謊言...
Don't accept the lie of religion...
社會主義...
socialism...
資本主義。
capitalism.
我們是個該死的物種。
We are a fucked species.
知道。希望是可以粉碎的。
Know it. Hope is smashable.
現實主義則不然。
Realism is not.
用真相保護自己。
Protect yourself with the truth.
我現在知道你是什麼了，哈利。
I realize what you are now, Harry.
只是一個無法承受世間痛苦的破碎小男孩。
Just a broken little boy
who cannot bear the pain of the world.
我想是這樣。
I suppose so.
再見，哈利。
Goodbye, Harry.
我們在馬賽被甩掉了。
We get thrown off in Marseille.
為什麼留在他身邊？
Why do you stay with him?
我總覺得這樣會更好。
I always think it will be better.
你當然知道。
'Course you do.
我聽過巴黎的美麗。
I have heard great things
of the beauty of Paris.
我他媽的會把你的狗踢死。
I'll fucking kick your dog to death.
他媽的...
Fucking...
巴黎沒錢。
Paris with no money.
- 你建議我們做什麼，貝拉？- 我會幫我們找一家旅館。
- What do you suggest we do, Bella?
- I will get us a hotel.
不用擔心。
Do not worry.
什麼？我們沒有錢。
With what? We have no money.
這不是一個有趣的實驗嗎？
Is it not an interesting experiment?
我們什麼都沒有。
We have nothing.
- 我們現在要怎麼生活？- 我不知道！
- How will we live now?
- I don't know!
沒錯，就是這個實驗。
Exactly, that is the experiment.
我們現在是窮人。
We are now the poor.
而且，許多冒險家都面臨過這些困難。
Also, many adventurers have faced these odds.
例如，魯賓遜漂流記。
Robinson Crusoe, for example.
自私、粗心、粗心的婊子。
Selfish, thoughtless, careless bitch.
我並不是粗心大意，鄧肯。
I'm not thoughtless, Duncan.
雖然我的能力確實如此...
And while it is true my ability...
透過思考事情得出合乎邏輯的結論並不是...
to think things through
to the logical conclusions is not...
強的...
strong...
我確實幫助了那些受苦受難的人。
I did help those suffering people.
我毀了我們...
I have ruined us...
正如你指出的...
as you pointed out...
但我確實相信我的行為來自一個好的地方。
but I do believe my actions
come from a good place.
他媽的閉嘴。
Shut the fuck up.
我會幫我們找一家旅館。
I will get us a hotel.
下午好，女士。
Good afternoon, madam.
美好的一天，我新鮮的、親愛的英國玫瑰。
Good day, my fresh, darling English Rose.
這是飯店嗎？
Is this a hotel?
我們有房間。
We have rooms.
你在找工作嗎？
Are you looking for work?
一間房多少錢？
How much is a room?
我將向你收取每小時 10 法郎的費用。
I'll charge you 10 francs an hour.
你收他們30。
You charge them 30.
每個人都很高興。
Everyone's happy.
我懂了。
I see.
查佩爾先生。
Monsieur Chapelle.
剛從倫敦回來。
Fresh from London.
你好。
Hello.
那麼，你走吧。
So, off you go.
此時我很困惑。
At this point, I am confused.
你不是來這裡工作的嗎？
You're not here to work?
快點。
Come on.
跟他躺在一起，讓他給你一點雞雞...
Lie with him, let him cock you a bit...
賺一些不錯的法郎。
and make some nice francs.
我懂了。
I see.
他會為此付錢給我嗎？
He would pay me for this?
是的。
Yes.
如果你需要錢...
If you need money...
這是到達它的最短路線。
it is the shortest route to it.
我從來沒有被別的男人欺負過...
I have never been cocked by another man...
但對此感到好奇。
and yet have wondered on that.
並且我需要資金。
And am in need of funds.
我相信，這是多種情況的結合...
It is, I believe,
a confluence of circumstances...
我認為幾乎是命運般的。
I regard as almost fate-like.
讓我們這樣做吧。
Let us do this.
16號房間。
Room 16.
你叫什麼名字？
What is your name?
神秘。
Mysterious.
我們是不是應該讓我暖和一點...
Should we warm me up a bit...
美好的一天，先生。
Good day, sir.
巧克力泡芙？
Éclair au chocolat?
我得到了一些錢，也得到了一些啟示。
I've come into some money
and some enlightenment.
你偷的？
You stole it?
你總是說你是世界上最好的寢具...
You've always said you're
the best bedman in the world...
我從未認識過其他人，所以我不知道這是否屬實。
and I have never known another,
so I knew not whether this was true.
但現在我知道了。
But now I do.
而且他很可怕...
And he was terrible...
當他插入我體內時，他發出了不敬虔的聲音。
and made ungodly noises
as he thrust himself into me.
鄧肯·韋德伯恩（Duncan Wedderburn）僅僅三下，他就只能做到了。
And a mere three thrusts, Duncan Wedderburn,
was all he could manage.
我忍住笑了…
I stifled a laugh...
當然，出於禮貌。
out of polites, of course.
我拿了他的錢。我向他道謝。
I took his money. I thanked him.
為了買給我們這些閃電泡芙，我一路笑著…
I laughed all the way
to buy us these eclairs...
我如此深情地想...
and I thought so fondly...
還記得我們那些汗流浹背的夜晚。
remembering the fierce sweaty nights of ours.
你他媽是為了錢嗎？
You fucked for money?
並作為一個實驗。
And as an experiment.
這對我們的關係有好處，因為它讓我對你的心感到高興。
And it is good for our relationship
as it gladdens my heart toward you.
最近我對你這個愛哭、愛罵髒話的人有點心灰意冷。
My heart has been a bit dim
on your weepy, sweary person lately.
你是個怪物。一個妓女和一個怪物。
You are a monster. A whore and a monster.
從地獄派來的惡魔…
A demon sent from hell...
將我的靈魂撕成碎片。
to rip my spirit to shreds.
為了懲罰我的小罪…
To punish my tiny sins...
伴隨著毀滅性的海嘯。
with a tsunami of destruction.
奪走我的心，像太妃糖一樣拉扯它…
To take my heart and pull it like taffy...
毀了我。
to ruin me.
我看著你，只看到醜陋。
I look at you,
and I see nothing but ugliness.
最後一點是沒有必要的，沒有意義...
That last bit was uncalled for
and makes no sense...
因為你對我的美麗的頌歌很無聊...
as your odes to my beauty have been boring...
但不變。
but constant.
還有這個簡單的動作...
And the simple act...
讓一個陌生男人騎在我身上...
of letting a strange man ride on me...
已經抹掉了這一切？
has erased all that?
他媽的！
Fuck!
你自己嫖娼了。
You whored yourself.
你現在要向我解釋的事情很糟糕。
Which you are now going to
explain to me is bad.
我和你永遠無法共贏嗎？
Can I never win with you?
這是女人能做的最糟糕的事。
It is the worst thing women can do.
我們絕對不該結婚。
We should definitely never marry.
我是一個有缺陷、喜歡嘗試的人...
I am a flawed, experimenting person...
我需要一個性情比較寬容的丈夫。
and I will need a husband
with a more forgiving disposition.
屄！
Cunt!
我現在看出你不是那樣的人。
I can now see you are not that.
我們的冒險顯然已經結束了。
Our adventure is clearly over.
我會給你訂一張回倫敦的機票。
I shall book you a passage back to London.
你有錢...
You had money...
一直這樣？
this whole time?
這是上帝的錢。
It is God's money.
用於緊急情況。
For emergencies.
幾個星期以來，這一直是個該死的緊急情況！
It has been a fucking emergency
for weeks now!
我一直相信你...
I believed in you the whole time...
你能應付自如。
that you would rise to the occasion.
但現在我發現那是個錯誤，而且你身上顯然有東西壞了。
But now I see that was a mistake,
and there's clearly something broken in you.
你破壞了我內心的某些東西！
You broke that something in me!
我覺得這次談話已經變成循環了。
I feel this conversation has become circular.
屄！
Cunt!
斯威尼女士，我已經檢查了我的情況。
Madam Swiney, I have examined my situation.
我需要性和金錢。
I need sex and money.
我可以找個情人...
I could take a lover...
另一個會留住我的韋德伯恩......
another Wedderburn who would keep me...
但可能需要大量的關注。
but may require an awful lot of attention.
不然一次就20分鐘了...
Or else it's 20 minutes at a time...
我剩下的時間可以自由地研究這個世界......
and the rest of my day
is free to study on the world...
以及它的改進。
and the improvement of it.
於是我就想找工作...
Hence, I seek employment...
在你散發著霉味的歡樂淫亂場所。
at your musty-smelling establishment
of good-time fornication.
一個女人正在策劃她的自由之路。
A woman plotting her course to freedom.
多麼令人愉快。
How delightful.
來。
Come.
薩維爾先生。
Monsieur Saveur.
菲力牛排。
A filet mignon.
優質切割。
A prime cut.
貝拉。
Bella.
最後說「厲害」 。
Say "formidable" at the end.
家庭規則。
House rules.
那味道是你嗎？
Is that smell you?
強大。
Formidable.
為了氣味。
For the smell.
還有茶。只因為茶好喝。
And tea. Just because tea is nice.
太殘酷了…
It was brutal...
以一種奇怪但並不令人不快的方式。
in a strangely not unpleasant way.
小冊子。
Pamphlet.
- 讀。- 那是什麼？
- Read.
- What is that?
一個想要…… 讓世界變得更美好的人。
Une personne qui veut...
change the world pour le meilleur.
讓它變得更好。一個更好的世界。
Make it better. A better world.
那我也是這樣了。
Then I am that too.
史維妮女士…
Madam Swiney...
這個陣容系統...
this lineup system...
你真的希望我和一個男人一起上樓，即使我覺得他令人厭惡...
you really expect me to go upstairs
with a man even if I find him distasteful...
因此我感到悲傷...
and therefore am sad...
當我讓他憤怒地跳我的時候？
when I let him furious jump me?
事情就是這樣，親愛的。
That is the way it is, my darling.
天哪，你看起來很漂亮。
Gosh, you look pretty.
你多麼同意被蹂躪。
How it agrees with you to be ravaged.
我想是這樣。
I suppose so.
那麼，如果女人選擇…你會不會更喜歡呢？
So, would you not prefer it
if the women chose...
因為這會是對你熱情的表現？
as it would be a sign of enthusiasm
toward you?
你不會隱約感覺到他們正處於恐怖狀態…
You wouldn't have the vague sense
that they are in a state of horror...
當你跳躍它們時。
when you jump them.
貝拉是新來的，可能有精神疾病。
Bella is new and may have a mental illness.
正如上帝、我的父親所說…
As God, my father, says...
這只是它的樣子，直到我們發現它的新方式...
it is only the way it is until we discover
the new way it is...
然後就是這樣，直到我們發現它的新方式...
and then that is the way it is
until we discover the new way it is...
如此下去，直到世界不再平坦......
and so it goes until the world
is no longer flat...
電照亮了夜晚，鞋子不再繫絲帶。
electricity lights the night,
and shoes are no longer tied with ribbons.
身為社會主義者，我完全同意。
As a socialist, I agree entirely.
圖瓦內特，你的嘴真聰明。
Toinette, you have such a clever mouth.
梅爾索先生將免費享用。
Monsieur Mersault will enjoy it for free.
去。現在。
Go. Now.
貝拉，在我辦公室一會兒。
Bella, a moment in my office.
你有看起來最美味的裂片。
You have the most delicious looking lobes.
謝謝。
Thank you.
我必須...
I must...
哦，對不起。我抽了血。
Oh, I am sorry. I drew blood.
這裡。
Here.
當我看到美麗、年輕的美麗時，有時我會屈服於自己。
I sometimes give in to myself
when I see beauty, young beauty.
有一天，親愛的...
For one day, my dear...
你將成為一個充滿皺紋的老軀殼。
you will be a wrinkled, old husk.
沒有人會希望您付費或免費獲得它。
And no one will want you either
to pay you for it or to have it for free.
我仍然相信，如果我們可以選擇，每個人都會更快樂。
I still believe everyone would be happier
if we could choose.
一個理想主義者。
An idealist.
像我這樣的。
Like me.
你是多麼令人愉快。
How delightful you are.
但有時我們必須屈服於世界的要求。
But we must give in to the demands
of the world sometimes.
與它搏鬥，試著打敗它。
Grapple with it, try to defeat it.
- 所以你跟我一樣相信嗎？- 當然。
- So you believe as me?
- Of course.
但有些男人卻享受你不喜歡的感覺。
But some men enjoy that you do not like it.
什麼？
What?
- 那是... - 生病了。
- That is...
- Sick.
不過生意不錯。
But good business.
跟我來。
Come with me.
我的孫子。
My grandchild.
生病而且身體不好，需要大量的醫生治療。
Sick and poorly,
and requiring much doctoring.
我給你選擇的選擇將會危害我的生意。
My choice of giving you choice
will jeopardize the business.
她的健康。她的一生。
Her health. Her life.
- 你想要那個嗎，貝拉？- 當然不是。
- Do you want that, Bella?
- Of course not.
你不這麼認為嗎？你真可愛。
You don't? You're so lovely.
我以為你是衝著我的肺葉去的
I thought you were going for my lobes.
我們必須工作。
We must work.
我們必須賺錢。
We must make money.
但更重要的是，我們必須經歷一切......
But more than that,
we must experience everything...
不僅僅是好的。
not just the good.
但墮落、恐懼、悲傷…
But degradation, horror, sadness...
這讓我們變得完整，貝拉。
This makes us whole, Bella.
使我們成為有內涵的人...
Makes us people of substance...
不是輕浮、未曾接觸過的孩子。
not flighty, untouched children.
然後我們就能認識世界。
Then we can know the world.
當我們了解這個世界時...
And when we know the world...
這個世界是屬於我們的。
the world is ours.
我要那個。
I want that.
現在...
Now...
去操某人吧...
go and fuck someone...
給我 10 法郎。
and bring me 10 francs.
首先，我建議進行一個小測驗。
First, I suggest a short quiz.
測驗？
A quiz?
你告訴我童年的記憶。
You tell me a childhood memory.
然後我講一個笑話。
Then I tell a joke.
然後快速嗅了嗅…
Then a quick sniff...
如有必要，請快速浸泡在薰衣草油中。
and if necessary,
a quick douse in lavender oil.
所有這些都將增強體驗，使其變得更加強大。
And all of this will enhance the experience
making it formidable.
不，我講笑話。
Non, I tell the joke.
你這個記憶。
You the memory.
當你小的時候在希臘，你從自行車上摔下來過嗎？
When you were little in Greece,
you fell from your bicycle?
血。順著我的腿下去。
Blood. Down my leg.
喜悅？
Joy?
你高興地看著血。
You watched the blood with joy.
敲，敲。
Knock, knock.
芝士來認識你。
Cheese to meet you.
你知道的。
You know it.
你聞起來還不錯。
You smell okay.
讓我們他媽的。
Let us fuck.
上帝給了你一份禮物，我的朋友。
God gave you a gift, my friend.
非常不優雅的工作。
Very inelegant work.
這就是你想家的時候所做的事？
This is what you do when you're homesick?
你想要什麼？
You wish what?
我的孩子們已經到了接受教育的年紀。性的。
My boys are of an age for education.
Sexual.
我會示範。
I will demonstrate.
我懂了。
I see.
有時。
At times.
我要躺著、彎腰、跨騎嗎？
Shall I lay, bend, astride?
讓我們從簡單的開始。
Let's start simple, please.
為了幫助事情進展...
To aid things along...
- 一根手指插在屁股上。- 不。
- a finger in the arse.
- No.
或者輕微的窒息也可能導致這種情況。
Or a slight choking may do it.
回家！
Go home!
貝拉！
Bella!
斯威尼女士是對的。
Madam Swiney was right.
我正在發現自己迄今為止未知的部分。
I am discovering parts of myself
hitherto unknown.
這是一種看待它的方式。
It is a way to look at it.
各種慾望的表現令人著迷。
The variety of desires being made manifest
is fascinating.
你有沒有那個男人...
Have you had the man...
誰把一塊鳳梨放進你嘴裡，然後讓你沾滿灰塵？
who puts a wedge of pineapple in your mouth
and covers you in dust?
貝拉。
Bella.
我幾乎準備好原諒你了。
I'm almost ready to forgive you.
我已經訂好回家的床位了...
I've booked our berths home...
我已經告訴媽媽準備我們的婚床了。
and I've told Mother
to prepare our wedding bed.
你操過那個手上有鉤子的傢伙嗎？
Did you fuck that guy with hooks for hands?
你做到了。我知道！
You did. I know!
我把那傢伙的焦油打掉了。
I beat the tar out of that guy.
鄧肯. 我以為你離開了
Duncan. I thought you left.
回到船上，但開始疼痛並嘔吐...
Back to the ship,
but started to ache and vomit...
所以我是來救你的。
so I'm here to save you.
你好，鄧肯。
Hello, Duncan.
回家吧，鄧肯。
Go home, Duncan.
我們的時代已經結束了。
Our time has ended.
我看著你，卻什麼感覺也沒有…
I look at you and feel nothing...
但揮之不去的問題是我如何想要你？
but the lingering question
of how did I ever want you?
我們必須去參加社會主義者的會議。
And we must go to the meeting of socialists.
你們是妓女。
You're whores.
我們是我們自己的生產資料。
We are our own means of production.
離開。
Go away.
腳。
Foot.
油漆, 腳.
Paint, foot.
非常好。
Very good.
語言雖然緩慢但正在進步。
Language is slow but improving.
畫。腳。
Paint. Foot.
天才。
Genius.
你能不能別對她這麼殘忍？
Can you not be so cruel to her?
我對貝拉犯了一個錯誤。
I made a mistake with Bella.
我允許感情發展。
I allowed feelings to develop.
沒有適合她的。她和雞狗沒什麼兩樣。
There are none for her.
She is no different to the chicken dog.
腳。
Foot.
也許這樣更好…
It is better this way, perhaps...
讓我了解到父親的冷靜。
and gives some insight
into my father's coolness to me.
這是科學的必然。
It was a necessity of science.
天哪，夥計。
Good God, man.
- 腳。- 我不指望你能理解...
- Foot.
- I do not expect you to understand...
鄉村醫生。
village doctor.
順便說一句，我需要你幫我做手術。
By the way, I need you to operate on me.
我應該將一顆跳動的心臟放入你的怪物形態中嗎？
Shall I put a beating heart
in your monstrous form?
如果你有時間...
If you have time...
當採取...
while taking...
這個出來了。
this out.
我會切除腫瘤周圍的一些囊腫。
I'll remove some cysts from around the tumor.
不需要。你可以把我關起來。
No need. You may close me up.
它已經蔓延了。我看到微小的息肉。
It has spread. I see tiny polyps.
我快死了。
I am dying.
怎麼把它給病人，嗯？
How to break it to the patient, eh?
巴克斯特...
Baxter...
不要哭到傷口！你會因為敗血症而更快殺死我。
Do not cry into the wound!
You'll kill me faster with sepsis.
現在安靜了。
Quiet now.
並把我關起來。
And close me up.
找她。
Find her.
我關門了。
I am closed.
熱巧克力，親愛的。
Hot chocolate, my dear.
還有巧克力的痛苦。
And pain au chocolat.
你是我的最愛。
You are my favorite.
我聽你對其他人說過這樣的話。
I have heard you say that to the others.
我們是一台你用讚美和巧克力餵養的機器。
We are a machine you feed
with compliments and chocolate.
你們是我的孩子，我用愛餵養。
You are my children I feed with love.
發生了可怕的事情，斯威尼。
Something terrible has happened, Swiney.
我幾乎什麼感覺都沒有。
I feel almost nothing.
我的同理心正逐漸朝著我所描述的方向發展…
My empathy is creeping
toward what I would describe...
作為輕蔑的憤怒。
as contemptuous rage.
這太棒了。
This is fabulous.
這是？
It is?
你正處於黑暗時期。
You're in the dark period.
在光明和智慧降臨到你之前。
Before light and wisdom come to you.
你必須克服它...
You must forge through it...
一旦到了另一邊...
and once on the other side...
你會感激這一刻，但你必須繼續前進。
you will be grateful to this moment,
but you must keep going.
我懂了。
I see.
你有嬰兒傷疤。
You've got a baby scar.
我的和媽媽一起。
Mine is with ma maman.
我沒有。
I don't have one.
這是事故留下的疤痕。
It is an accident scar.
但你並不是第一個犯這個錯的人。
But you're not the first
to have made the mistake.
為什麼說謊？
Why lie?
我不是說假話。
I'm not lying.
我的戈德溫親口告訴我的。
My Godwin told me himself.
韋德伯恩。
Wedderburn.
美好的一天，先生。
Good day, sir.
您寫信給戈德溫‧巴克斯特先生。
You wrote to Mr. Godwin Baxter.
他派出了一個逍遙法外的惡魔到這個世界。
He has sent a demon at large into the world.
惡魔包裹在無法滿足的誘人肉體中…
The devil's wrapped in an alluring body
that cannot be satiated...
以及一顆將人們一針一線分開的心靈…
and a mind that picks people apart
stitch by stitch...
就像從大象屁股拉出來的一個血跡斑斑、燒焦的布娃娃。
like a bloodied and burned rag doll
shat out of an elephant's arse.
貝拉。
Bella.
她在哪？
Where is she?
你是誰？
Who are you?
我是她的未婚夫 先生
I'm her fiancé, sir.
顯然，你們之間的事並沒有好結果。
Obviously, things did not end well
between you.
沒有？
Did not?
她毀了我。
She destroyed me.
好吧，我們都是自己這艘船的主人，長官。
Well, we're all masters of our own ship, sir.
就是這樣。
There's that.
我不喜歡你或你的話。
I do not like you or your words.
那個戈德溫·巴克斯特。
That Godwin Baxter.
他知道，所以他叫她來找我。
He knew, and he set her on to me.
他困住了我。
He trapped me.
她在哪？
Where is she?
不希望她成為我最大的敵人。
Would not wish her on my worst enemy.
我會把你從她手中救出來，先生。
I shall save you from her, sir.
原諒我的沮喪。就告訴我嘛。
Forgive my frustration. Just tell me.
它不痛。
It does not hurt.
我沒有內臟。
I have no insides.
她把我掏空了。
She hollowed me out.
我的靈魂。我的銀行帳戶！
My soul. My bank account!
我是一個蟲！如地獄！
I am a bug! A shell!
我們唱歌吧？
Shall we sing?
哦，我們是水手...
Oh, we are sailors...
它不...
It doesn't...
不疼。
Doesn't hurt.
我不希望事情變成這樣。
I do not wish it to be like this.
你強迫我的手。
You force my hand.
“我們都是自己這艘船的主人。”
"We're all masters of our own ship."
你這個滿嘴賤貨的死東西。
You cunting cunt-faced deadshit.
請。
Please.
我盡可能禮貌地問你。
I ask you as politely as I can.
她在哪？
Where is she?
妓女回來了。
The whore is back.
上帝？
God?
貝拉！
Bella!
麥克斯寫信給我。
Max wrote me.
- 你生病了？- 我不是。我快死了。
- You are ill?
- I am not. I am dying.
這是一個微妙的差異，但作為一名醫生，我認真對待這一差異。
A subtle difference,
but one I take seriously as a physician.
你是一道風景，也是個好人。
You are a sight and a good one.
你不能死。
You cannot die.
經驗數據的說法不同。
Empirical data says different.
我很想念你。
I missed you.
我現在必須躺下。
I now have to lie down.
我帶來的並不全是陽光。
It is not all sunshine I bring.
我還帶來了明亮的眼睛和尖銳的問題。
I also bring beady eyes and hard questions.
我心裡有小孩嗎？
Did I have a baby in me?
如果是的話，它在哪裡？
And if so, where is it?
我懂了。
I see.
好吧，從技術上講，你是你的孩子。
Well, technically, you are your baby.
而且，我想你是你的母親。
And also, I suppose you are your mother.
也都不是。
And also neither.
沒有記憶倖存。
No memory survives.
任何經歷都無法生存。
No experiences survive.
我是母女是什麼意思？
What do you mean I am mother and daughter?
你知道但沒有告訴。
You knew and did not tell.
我沒有看到好的理由。
I did not see good reason to.
而且我們太膽怯了。
And were too cowardly to.
也有一點這樣的。
A bit of that as well.
我想和你在一起...
I wanted to be with you...
我不確定你是否能理解。
and I was not sure you would even understand.
巴克斯特有點讓人成為他的俘虜。
And Baxter kind of makes one a prisoner
to him.
而我是...
And I am...
對不起。
I'm sorry.
嘭。
Bam.
這是誰？
Who is this?
貝爾妓女
Bell whore
- 貝爾妓女 - 我看到你已經介紹我了，波麗姆。
- Bell whore
- I see you've introduced me then, Prim.
- 不過我喜歡這個。 - 貝爾妓女
- I like this one though.
- Bell whore
- 現在夠了，費莉西蒂... - 貝爾妓女
- That's enough now, Felicity...
- Bell whore
笨蛋。
Fucker.
另一個？
Another one?
我們想你。
We missed you.
怪物。
Monsters.
噢，該死的。
Oh, fucking hell.
貝爾妓女
Bell whore
處於想要打人的位置是很困難的…
It is hard to be in the position
where one wants to hit someone...
誰已經處於明顯的痛苦之中。
who is already in obvious pain.
這肯定是一個難題。
It is a conundrum for sure.
你願意成為一塊鼻子裡插著魚鉤的灰色肉塊嗎？
Would you rather be a gray slab of flesh
with a fishhook in your nose?
我會感覺良好一秒鐘，但會感覺更糟糕，所以......
I will feel good for a second,
but bad for longer, so...
我鼻子真的有魚鉤嗎？
I really had a fishhook in my nose?
你做到了。
You did.
所以，我是你的創造物…
So, I am your creation...
另一個也是如此。
as is the other one.
你們都不是那樣的人。
Neither of you are that.
她拿著錘子，唱著歌在大廳裡漫步…
She wanders the halls
with a hammer and a song...
那不是我做的。
and that is not my doing.
我讀了你的卡片和回家的信......
And I read your cards and letters home...
看著你無所畏懼地創造出貝拉·巴克斯特，並驚嘆不已。
and watched you fearlessly
create Bella Baxter with wonder.
我發現活著很有趣，所以我會原諒你的行為...
I am finding being alive fascinating,
so I'll forgive you the act...
但始終討厭隨之而來的謊言和陷阱。
but always hate the lies and trapping
that followed.
明白了。
Understood.
很高興見到你。
Good to see you.
你也是。
You too.
拋開憤怒、困惑和大腦失調不談，我想念你。
Anger, confusion, and brain dissonance aside,
I missed you.
回到家，我聞到了甲醛的味道…
I arrived home,
and I smelled the formaldehyde...
我知道接下來會發生什麼事。
and I knew what is next.
我會成為一名醫生。
I will be a doctor.
我的手術就是你的了。
My surgery is yours.
我父親曾經告訴我...
My father once told me...
總是懷著慈悲心去雕刻。
always carve with compassion.
他真是個白痴。
He was a fucking idiot.
但這並不是一個壞建議。
But it's not bad advice.
他的時間不多了。
He does not have long.
我知道。
I know.
你還沒提到我們訂婚的事。
You've not mentioned our betrothal.
你年輕得多。
You were much younger.
沒有綁定。
There is no bind.
我被你迷住了，巴克斯特利用了這一點。
I was mesmerized by you,
and Baxter took advantage.
那麼，你不再著迷了嗎？
So, you are mesmerized no more?
我仍然著迷。
I am still mesmerized.
我曾經是個妓女，你懂嗎？
I've been a whore, you understand?
我體內的雞雞為了錢。
Cocks for money inside me.
你同意嗎？
You okay with that?
嫖娼的事情是否會挑戰慾望…
Does the whoring thing
challenge the desire...
為了男人擁有的所有權？
for ownership that men have?
韋德伯恩變得非常哭泣和咒罵...
Wedderburn became much weepy and sweary...
當他發現我嫖娼的時候。
when he discovered my whoring.
我發現自己只是嫉妒男人們和你在一起的時間...
I find myself merely jealous
of the men's time with you...
而不是對你進行任何道德誹謗。
rather than any moral aspersion against you.
這是你的身體，貝拉·巴克斯特。
It is your body, Bella Baxter.
你的自由奉獻。
Yours to give freely.
我一般收30法郎。
I generally charged 30 francs.
嗯，這看起來很低。
Well, that seems low.
你相信人是可以進步的嗎，麥克斯？
Do you believe people improvable, Max?
我願意。
I do.
就像人體的疾病可以被治癒一樣...
Just as a human body
can be cured of illness...
所以男人和女人都可以治癒方面。
so can men and women be cured of aspect.
馬克斯·麥坎德爾斯，你願意嫁給我嗎？
Will you marry me, Max McCandles?
我會。
I will.
以後我們會少用你的舌頭......
We will need less of your tongue
in the future...
但總的來說，最令人愉快的。
but overall, most agreeable.
我會記下那張紙條。
I will take that note.
還有你檢查過有沒有疾病嗎？
And have you been checked for disease?
我沒有，但我會的。
I have not, but I shall.
我很享受我們之間這種實際的愛。
I'm enjoying this practical love we have.
但我向你保證我也充滿熱情。
But I assure you mine is also passionate.
你好可愛。
You are adorable.
你一直都是。
You always were.
天啊，你在行走。
God, you are walking.
我因疼痛而透過腳趾注射了五毫克海洛因...
I have taken five milligrams of heroin
through the toes for pain...
安非他明作為能量...
amphetamines for energy...
和可卡因，因為我偏愛可卡因。
and cocaine because I am partial to cocaine.
我來這裡是為了陪你走上紅毯。
I've come here to walk you down the aisle.
因此，根據教會賦予我的權力......
And so, by the powers vested in me
by the church...
我將為這次結合舉行隆重儀式。
I shall solemnize this union.
貝拉·巴克斯特，你願意接受這個男人當你的丈夫嗎？
Do you, Bella Baxter,
take this man as your husband?
我們是否錯過了關於有人反對這一點的部分？
Did we miss the part
about anyone objecting to this?
或者說，這一點已經在教義問答的某種虛假現代化中被刪除了？
Or has that been removed in some kind
of faux modernization of the catechism?
你好，維多利亞。
Hello, Victoria.
你看起來不錯。
You look well.
先生，您指的是我嗎？
Do you refer to me, sir?
男人通常不會向妻子介紹自己。
A man doesn't normally introduce himself
to his wife.
但如果我必須...
But if I must...
他是這一切的神。
He is the God of it.
我不知道是他在她的掌控之中，還是她在他的掌控之中。
I do not know if he's in her power
or she in his.
這是魔鬼手頭上的工作。看！
'Tis Devil's work at hand.
Look!
他咳​​出的不是正常人的空氣，而是血液。
He coughs not air as a normal man
but blood.
他得了癌症，你這個白痴。
He has cancer, you fucking idiot.
鄧肯.
Duncan.
別用你的眼睛看著我，惡魔！
Do not lay your eyes on me, demon!
正如我所說，阿爾弗雷德·布萊辛頓將軍。
As I was saying, General Alfred Blessington.
“阿爾菲”給你。
"Alfie" to you.
你真的不認識我嗎？
You really do not know me?
當韋德伯恩先生把你的照片登在報紙上時...
When Mr. Wedderburn
put your photo in the paper...
我記得飯店裡那個老鳥叫你維多利亞·布萊辛頓…
I remembered that old bird in the hotel
called you Victoria Blessington...
我把這個惡魔般的亂七八糟的拼圖拼湊在一起。
and I pieced this diabolical fuckfest
of a puzzle together.
- 你是... - 你親愛的阿爾菲。
- You are...
- Your dear Alfie.
在懷孕期間，您處於某種精神錯亂和歇斯底里的狀態。
You left in a state of some mental addlement
and hysteria over your pregnancy.
發現你不在後，我感到心如死灰。
On the discovery of your absence,
I felt disemboweled.
我在戰場上把人開膛破肚…
I have disemboweled men
on the field of battle...
我總是想像一種沉悶、空洞的悸動…
and I always imagined a dull,
hollow throbbing...
事情就是這樣。
and that is what it was like.
還有一股惡臭，但這並不適用於這裡作為比喻。
There's also a stench,
but that does not apply as a metaphor here.
但你在這裡，我親愛的。
But here you are, my darling.
給你。
Here you are.
上帝。
God.
我對你沒有任何記憶。
I have no recollection of you.
我是貝拉·巴克斯特。
I am Bella Baxter.
傷人的。
Hurtful.
但也許你已經撞到頭了......
But perhaps you've hit your head...
這些人顯然利用了你。
and these men have clearly taken
advantage of you.
請走吧，先生。
Please go, sir.
- 你是我的丈夫？- 你親愛的阿爾菲。
- You were my husband?
- Your dear Alfie.
貝拉，對不起。
Bella, I'm sorry.
其實我很想去。
Actually, I would like to go.
什麼？
What?
貝拉？
Bella?
先生，您有馬車嗎？
You have a carriage, sir?
是的。
Yes.
那我們走吧。
Let us go then.
貝拉！
Bella!
讓我走吧，上帝。
Let me go, God.
麥克斯，你不會阻止我的。
Max, you will not stop me.
很高興你回來了，維多利亞。
It is good to have you back, Victoria.
我和僕人相處得併不好。
The servants and I
have not been getting along.
我害怕起義。
I fear an uprising.
你還記得大衛嗎，親愛的？
You remember David, darling?
艾莉森，看看誰回來了。
Allison, look who's back.
你了解我？
You know me?
告訴我關於我自己的事。
Tell me about myself.
我很好嗎？
Was I nice?
吃。
Eat.
都是你的最愛。
All your favorites.
醃魚、鵝...
Kippers, goose...
舌頭, 香檳.
tongue, champagne.
我很想念你。
I've missed you.
不快樂的根源是什麼？
What was the root of the unhappiness?
到底是什麼原因讓她跳下橋呢？
What drove her to leap off the bridge?
你討厭這個孩子。
You hated the baby.
你稱它為「怪物」。
You called it "the monster."
我懂了。
I see.
我注意到缺乏母性本能。
I have noticed a lack of maternal instinct.
但我很高興你能回家。
And yet I'm happy to have you home.
我們是怎麼認識的？
How did we meet?
在一個舞會上。
At a ball.
我們為什麼互相喜歡？
Why did we like each other?
我們共同熱愛美好時光。
We shared a love of good times.
手錶。
Watch.
艾莉森，湯！
Allison, soup!
雷克斯！
Rex!
他媽的！
Fuck!
艾莉森...
Allison...
如果可以的話我們會吃一些起司。
we'll have some cheese when you can.
是對殘酷的熱愛嗎？
A love of cruelty?
- 看來我不是個善良的人。- 種類？
- I was not a kind person, it seems.
- Kind?
你永遠不會這麼遲鈍，維多利亞。
You would never be so dull, Victoria.
令人震驚的想法。
Appalling idea.
韋德伯恩說你是個妓女。
Wedderburn says you were a whore.
- 我懷疑那是一部分... - 我是。
- I suspect that was part...
- I was.
在巴黎。
In Paris.
我厭倦了它，但它很迷人。
I tired of it, but it was fascinating.
- 正確的。- 這些醃魚非常美味。
- Right.
- These kippers are strangely delicious.
醋什麼的。
Vinegary or something.
婚姻是一個持續的挑戰。
Marriage is a constant challenge.
有些，我們屈服，有些我們屈服。
Some, we bend to, some we bend to us.
我會盡力原諒你的嫖娼行為。
I will try to forgive you for the whoring.
你的性歇斯底里常常失控。
Your sexual hysteria was often out of hand.
以及殺害我們未出生的孩子。
And for the killing of our unborn child.
事實上，當我列出你冤枉我的方式時...
In fact, when I list the ways
you've wronged me...
耶穌基督自己可能會用球棒敲打你的頭。
Jesus Christ himself would probably
beat your head in with a bat.
你很幸運有一個寬容的丈夫。
You're blessed with a forgiving husband.
我沒有冤枉你，阿爾菲…
I've not wronged you, Alfie...
因為我不認識你。
as I do not know you.
嗯，你很幸運，因為我在失憶症領域有很多經驗。
Well, you're in luck as I've had a lot
of experience in the field with amnesia.
要嘛是那些想忘記自己身在何處的人…
Either men who wish to forget
where they were...
或迫擊砲在附近爆炸.....
or a mortar exploded nearby...
像教堂的鐘聲一樣敲響他們的頭蓋骨。
ringing their cranium like a church bell.
我建議我們在房子附近待幾個月...
I suggest we stick close to the house
for several months...
也許一年。
maybe a year.
直到您完全康復。
Until you've made a full recovery.
我會在閒暇時離開，但你想困住我讓我受寵若驚。
I will leave at my leisure,
but I am flattered by your desire to trap me.
你不是第一個。
You're not the first.
我他媽得朝你的頭開槍…
I will have to shoot you
in the fucking head...
如果你想離開，親愛的。
if you try to leave, darling.
頭的前面還是後面？
The front or the back of the head?
背部。
The back.
為了確定你要離開...
As to be sure you were leaving...
我並沒有魯莽。
and I was not being rash.
我想念你。
I have missed you.
那麼，我是一個囚犯嗎？
So, I'm a prisoner?
這場談話走上了一條不幸的道路。
This conversation has gone down
an unfortunate route.
我相信你會像以前一樣快樂。
I am sure you will be as happy
as you were before.
和我之前從橋上跳下去時一樣嗎？
As I was before
when I threw myself from a bridge?
我懷疑你是在找魚的時候跌倒的。
I suspect you fell while looking for fish.
如果我不想留下來，為什麼要把我留在這裡？
Why would you want to keep me here
if I do not wish to stay?
如果一個人必須淹死，就讓它在愛河裡吧。
If one must drown,
let it be in the river of love.
大衛...
David...
那隻雉雞看起來是不是被剝得只剩骨頭了？
does that pheasant look stripped to the bone?
這是一個誤判，先生。
It was a misjudgment, sir.
我道歉。
I apologize.
親愛的，甜點嗎？
Dessert, darling?
很容易脫落嗎？
It comes off easy?
就像西裝上的羈扣。
Like a button on a suit.
我在非洲看到他們用削尖的石頭做這件事...
I saw them do it in Africa
with sharpened rocks...
但我自己製作了更精確的設備。
but had my own more precise device made.
你想要的只是陰蒂罩...
Do you want just clitoral hood...
或者龜頭也是如此？
or glans as well?
整個地獄包。
The whole infernal packet.
這會讓她平靜下來。
It will calm her no end.
這次我們會完成它。
This time we will get it done.
今晚我會給她注射鎮定劑並帶她去你的手術室。
I shall get her sedated
and bring her to your surgery this evening.
維多利亞，親愛的！
Victoria, darling!
你在哪裡？
Where are you?
時間恰好。
Perfect timing.
馬提尼。
Martini.
而不是。
Rather not.
然而，我想離開。
I would, however, like to leave.
我發現我們在一起的時光很有趣...
I have found our time together interesting...
但我已經弄清楚為什麼我從橋上跳下去了。
but I've ascertained
why I jumped from a bridge.
我想見見我那瀕臨死亡的上帝。
I wish to go see my near dead God.
可愛的主意。
Adorable idea.
不幸的是，我親愛的...
Unfortunately, my darling...
我的一生致力於奪取領土。
my life is dedicated
to the taking of territory.
你是我的...
You are mine...
這就是它的長處和短處。
and that is the long and short of it.
我不是領地。
I am not territory.
問題的根源在於你的雙腿之間。
The root of the problem is between your legs.
我會把它摘下來...
I will have it off...
它不會再讓你分心或轉移注意力。
and it will not distract
and divert you anymore.
你看，一個男人一生都在與自己的性衝動奮戰。
You see, a man spends his life
wrangling his sexual compulsions.
這是一個詛咒，但從某些方面來說，這是他畢生的事業。
It's a curse and yet,
in some ways, his life's work.
女人一生的工作就是孩子。
A woman's life's work is children.
我打算把你兩腿之間的那個可惡的包去掉...
I intend to rid you of that infernal packet
between your legs...
然後立即在你身上種下一顆種子。
and plant a seed in you straight after.
讓我解釋一下發生了什麼事。
Let me explain what has happened.
你的妻子維多利亞從橋上跳下身亡。
Victoria, your wife, threw herself
from a bridge and died.
戈德溫·巴克斯特找到了她，帶她去了他的手術室。
Godwin Baxter found her,
brought her to his surgery.
然後他取出了嬰兒，取出了嬰兒的大腦...
He then removed the baby,
removed the brain from the baby...
將它移植到我的大腦中並讓我復活。
transplanted it into my head
and reanimated me.
我會把文件帶給你。這實際上非常令人著迷。
I'll bring you the file.
It's actually quite fascinating.
不過，我會繼續我的新生活…
However, I will keep my new life...
還有我可愛的老陰蒂，謝謝你。
and my lovely old clitoris, thank you.
如果你願意幫我叫一輛馬車的話。
If you'd call a carriage for me.
他們說啊說啊…
They talk and talk...
但到了某個時候，除了拔槍之外別無他法。
and yet at some point there's nothing left
but to pull a gun.
這就是對待女人的方式。
'Tis the way with women.
你屈服了嗎？
Are you giving in?
我寧願你朝我他媽的心臟開一槍。
I'd rather you shot me in the fucking heart.
如果有必要的話我會答應的。
I will oblige if I have to.
喝點飲料吧，親愛的。
Drink the drink, darling.
氯仿和杜松子酒。
Chloroform and gin.
從某些方面來說，擺脫自我探索會讓我鬆一口氣。
In some ways it would be a relief
to be rid of my questing self.
深深地啜飲，自由就屬於你了。
Sip deeply and that freedom is yours.
他媽的。
Fuck.
最大限度？
Max?
最大限度。我們必須讓他接受手術。
Max. We have to get him to surgery.
如果我們不這麼做他就會死
He'll die if we don't.
流血很多。
Bleeding a lot.
你他媽死定了。
You're fucking dead.
貝拉，如果他還活著的話…
Bella, if he lives...
我不認為他是一個會停下來的人。
I do not sense he is a man who will stop.
好吧，我不會看著他流血而死。
Well, I won't watch him bleed to death.
但我同意，他還需要改進。
But I agree, he could do with improvement.
我已經取出子彈並止血了。
I've removed the bullet
and stopped the bleeding.
我有筆記。
I have the notes.
我從來沒有比在這裡更開心的了。
I am never happier than when I'm in here.
貝拉。
Bella.
你回來了。
You're back.
這只是別人的故事…
It was just a story of someone else...
不是貝拉·巴克斯特。
not Bella Baxter.
我的一生，人們的目光都看著我......
All my life, people's eyes looked at me...
恐怖、可惜…
horror, pity...
但是你。
but you.
這一切都非常有趣...
It's all very interesting...
怎麼了。
what is happening.
解剖學考試讓我很緊張。
Anatomy exam is making me nervous.
我已經多次考驗你了。你知道的。
I've tested you many times. You know it.
沒有人比你更了解解剖學。
No one knows anatomy better than you.
女士們，琴酒嗎？
Ladies, gin?
請。
Please.
杜松子酒？
Gin?
我們應該要給將軍弄點水。
We should get some water for the general.
費莉西蒂...
Felicity...
水。
water.